《斯巴达克斯：血与沙》
《陷坑》
你把我当傻瓜么？
Do you think me a fool?
没有 主人
No, Dominus.
可你却不尊重我
Yet you dishonor me.
跟我达成协议 许下誓言！
An agreement reached, an oath sworn!
获准参加角斗训练
You would submit to gladiatorial training.
叫我主人
Call me master,
遵守规则！
attend to the rules!
作为回报 我去帮你找
In return, I would search for
你心爱的妻子！
your precious wife!
但你的急躁毁了你自己
But your haste bested you.
藐视Doctore 用计争了个机会
Defying Doctore, maneuvering to usurp gnaeus
到竞技场上和Crixus对决
to face Crixus in the arena.
你的第一次角斗赛！
Your first contest!
和Crixus对打！
With Crixus!
那要命的卡普亚战神！
The champion of fucking Capua!
我知道错了
I realize the mistake in it.
知错？
Mistake?
靠 你万众瞩目！
Fuck, you had the crowd!
你逃过了死刑
You survived execution
打败了4个Solonius的人！
against four of Solonius' men!
你人尽皆知！
Your name was on every tongue!
可现在跟Crixus打过以后
Now after your showing with Crixus,
你就成了笑柄！
it's spoken of with contempt!
你的小失误 会搞砸
Your little mistake makes reunion
和妻子重聚的机会
with your wife problematic.
你有她的消息了？
You have knowledge of her?
目前只知道 那个从Glaber手上
The Syrian Glaber sold her to
买了她的叙利亚人向北去了
was last noted heading north.
我们还不知道他们的目的地
We've yet to divine their destination.
你得接着找她
You must keep searching for her.
你毁了那么重要的约定
You shit on honorable agreements
还有脸向我提要求？
and press for fresh demands?
告诉我 色雷斯人
Tell me, Thracian,
如果找到她 你愿为她的自由付多少钱？
how will you pay for her release if found?
如果她能回来呢？
Her transport?
你能下个金蛋来瞧瞧吗？
Do you shoot magic coins out of your ass?
要是行的话 马上给我下出来！
If so, squat and produce!
我会去竞技场角斗 我的赏金…
I shall fight in the arena, my winnings…
没人乐意看你上场！
No one wishes to see you fight!
民众的喜爱 像风一样 稍纵即逝
The crowd's favor, like the wind, is fleeting.
他们对你没兴趣了
Their interest in you has blown out.
天无绝人之路
There must be a way for me to fight.
只有一条路
Only one.
去那个不需要遵守规则的地方吧
In a place where you needn't follow rules,
因为根本无规则可循
because none exist.
地下竞技赌场
The pits of the underworld.
去那儿比试 不死的话
Fight there and survive,
你就能赚得盆钵满盈
and you will fill both our hands with coin.
还有…
And…
或许可以和妻子再度聚首哦
you may yet feel your wife's touch again.
色雷斯贱种
Thracian bitch.
Barca！放开他！
Barca! Release!
我觉得 你应该把你妻子的绑带留下
I think your wife's binding should remain here.
你到那儿去 可能会把它弄丢
Where you're going, you might lose it.
跟你的胳膊一起 不复存在
Along with an arm.
把他收拾妥当
Finish preparing him.
我能说句话么 主人？
A word, Dominus?
如果快的话
If hastened.
竞技赌场的流言将一日千里
The walls spread rumor of the pits.
你有异议？
You find objection to this course?
那是个炼狱
It is a place of pain and suffering,
人命贱如草
beasts dying without honor.
您父亲绝不会…
Your father would never have…
我意已定！
The decision is made!
如果野人驯服不了 那就让他野个够
If a beast cannot be tamed, it must be unleashed.
如果雨季来了
If the rains ever return,
我要好好淋上一个礼拜
I shall soak in a bath for a week.
啊 来点香水
Ahh, perfume.
只剩几滴了 主人
Only a few drops remain, Domina.
给天神留着吧
I shall save them for Jupiter.
我要用它祭坛祈祷
I will douse his altar and pray
让这香味引来洪水
that the scent sparks a deluge.
你看到我的短剑没？它不见了
Have you seen my dagger? It eludes me.
要它来干嘛？
What purpose requires it?
我找到条金河
I've divined an additional stream of revenue.
可以让我们痛快洗浴
One that will provide us a proper bath.
那这条金河
And this stream,
源自哪里？
it flows from what orifice?
竞技赌场
The pits.
听着 只有Crixus一人在训练场一枝独秀
Look, Crixus remains the single draw of the ludus.
在所有的新人理 Varro是唯一值得信任的人
Of the new recruits, Varro is the only man of promise.
斯巴达克斯和Kerza 在竞技场显得毫无价值
Spartacus and Kerza prove worthless in the arena.
所以 我今晚让他俩去那里
So I fight them both tonight where they may yet
或许可以充实我们的钱包
fill our purse.
Quintus呀
Quintus.
派遣特雷斯人 让我松了一口气
Dispatching the Thracian brings me relief.
你已经深陷竞技赌场 无法自拔了
You descending into the pits does not.
那样会玷污名誉 也会威胁生命
It stains the name, and threatens the body.
我会受到很好的保护
My body will be well protected.
Barca随身保护 随时准备
Barca looms over it, ready to break bone
将来犯之人撕成碎片
at the slightest provocation.
告诉Barca 如果你有什么闪失
Inform Barca that if you return scathed,
我就把他弟弟切下来装罐子里
I'll have his cock in a jar.
信息会被忠实地传达到位
The message will be dutifully delivered.
今晚给Crixus一个女人
Give Crixus a woman tonight.
刺激下其他人 让他们知道
Motivation to the others that success brings
胜利可以带来很多好处
decoration in many forms.
我来看他享受
I'll see him well satisfied.
快走 你他妈的！
Keep moving you fuck!
他们要带他去哪？
Where do they take him?
去地下赌场 属于他的地方
To the underworld, where he belongs.
专心训练！
Back to training!
告诉我 我可不像你这样
Tell me I don't look like I have been shit
跟被操死的野猪肉一样
from a boar's ass like you.
我不要死在竞技赌场
I am not dying in the pits.
我要给他们看看 我他妈是
I'll show these fucking cunts my cock
经过火神千锤百炼的
was forged in Vulcan's flames.
我要把他们全操一遍！
I will fuck them all!
撕开他的屁股！
Tear his ass open!
砸烂他的头！
Rip his head off!
起来 起来 你这没用的…
Get up, get up, you useless…
靠
Shit.
靠！
Shit!
Ovidius来了
Ovidius approaches.
Ovidius 很高兴你也下赌啊！
Ovidius, good to lay eyes!
我也希望早点下赌啊
I had expected them laid earlier.
我们协议说的可是 你要在
Our agreement calls for repayment of your debt
火神节比赛结束后的第二天
plus thirty percent, to be delivered
把欠我的债和三分利 一起还给我
the day after the games of the Vulcanalia.
但我却发现你在这儿
Yet I find you here,
赌注你还欠着呢
Wagering coin still owed.
我跟你保证 你会第一个收到应付款
You'll be first to receive what is due, I assure you.
双面神说的都是假话
Words spewed by Janus,
无论从哪边的脸说出来 都一样
from both sides of his face.
你很快会收到钱的
You'll be repaid soon enough.
除非你想自找麻烦？
Unless you'd care to press the matter?
那你就自便吧
At your convenience then.
不管到什么时候
Until such time,
利息依然照算
the points still accrue.
拽个屁
Ass eating shit.
再敢这样跟我说话 我把你打成猪头
Speak to me such again, I will accrue your fucking head.
Ixion 获胜！
Ixion, victor!
谁敢跟我打？
You want to face me?
愿天神眷顾你 色雷斯人
May the gods fare you better, Thracian.
也眷顾我们
For both our sakes.
你没戴我送你的礼物
Your neck is bare of my gift.
没错
It is.
那么 是你不喜欢它？
You did not favor it, then?
不喜欢我送你的项链？
The necklace I gave you?
小声点
Lower your voice.
你的礼物 我不能接受
Your gift, I cannot accept it.
抱歉
Pardon my mistake.
你该知道 如果主人…
You must understand, if Domina…
你已经解释清楚了
You've made your intention clear.
你会激动吗？
Does it excite you?
当得知你的脚步 可以让我
To know that your very footsteps
心潮澎湃的时候？
moisten my thighs?
我会让你更澎湃
I would have them dripping even more.
那就赶紧过来吧
Well draw closer and make it so.
你握着什么？
What are you clutching?
给我瞧瞧
Show me.
一个寒碜的礼物
A humble gift.
送给我的女神
For a goddess.
给我戴上吧
Put it on.
你开心吗？
Does it please you?
嗯
Yes.
眼观困兽
Witness the captive beasts,
让我们饮血止渴吧！
quenching our thirst with blood!
在竞技赌场死去…
Set to die in the pits…
是他们逆天而生的报应！
Payment for their offensive births!
让死神重新降临吧！
Let death descend anew!
有请 Myrmex！
Behold, Myrmex!
有请 斯巴达克斯！
Behold, Spartacus!
大家似乎不喜欢他
The crowd does not seem to favor him.
他在竞技场捅了那篓子后 这样不奇怪吧？
Why would they, after his showing in the arena?
上天
What weapons
将赐予他们何种武器？
shall the gods bless them with?
亦或天谴他们
Or curse them
空手作战！
with empty hands!
为自己的命运做出选择吧！
Choose your fate!
Myrmex选了钢刺手套！
Myrmex draws sphairai!
斯巴达克斯选了铜圈手套！
Spartacus draws caestus!
Myrmex更占优势
Myrmex has the advantage.
谢谢你的多嘴
Thank you for the fucking obvious.
我们只有一条简单的规则！
We have but a single rule!
只能有一个活下来！
Only one survives!
撕扯对战
Mongrel on mongrel,
直到死神降临！
till Charon arrives!
赔率是怎么定的？
What do you make of the odds?
我方4：1的赔率
Four to one against our man.
或许是5：1
Maybe five.
在斯巴达克斯身上 押10迪纳币
Place ten denarii on Spartacus.
希望能有大回报
And pray for ample return.
遵命 主人
Dominus.
还手呀！
Do something!
斯巴达克斯！胜利！
Spartacus! Victor!
让他稍事休息 再打
Give him a moment's rest, then fight him again.
你受伤了
You're hurt.
我没事
I'm all right.
别把自己逼得太狠了
You push yourself too far.
可我还活着
And yet I live.
还能活多久？
For how long?
能有多久 就多久
As long as it takes.
那就把他们全杀了
Then kill them all.
你还想回竞技赌场去吗？
Do you plan to return to the pits?
他们让我们赚得盆钵满盈…
They fill our hands with coin…
而且还能赚得更多
With yet more to be mined.
满盘皆输的那天该怎么办？
And what when the shaft caves in on you?
那该怎么办？
What then?
你知道法律的规定 没有继承人的话
You know the law, without an heir
我得被迫嫁给别人
I'd be forced to marry another.
你希望这样吗？让别人来碰我？
Is that what you want? Someone else's hands upon me?
我要天下万物！
I want everything!
可现在什么都没有
Yet can afford nothing.
我只在乎你 Quintus
My concerns only with you, Quintus.
如果没有你 我肯定
If you're lost, my reason for breath
活不下去
would surely follow.
我活得好好儿的 别想那些触霉头的事
I remain firmly rooted, banish it from thought.
斯巴达克斯玩儿完 我就收手
When Spartacus ends, so does my time in the pits.
那时 他早给我们赚够了
Till then, his victories swell our purse.
很快又会被你花光的
Which you deflate with new purchases.
这小玩意儿？
This simple thing?
我今天才找回来的 可开心呢
Its rediscovery today pleased me.
是我妈妈的 当初跟她的东西一起不见了
It was my mother's, lost amongst her things.
不求奢华的女人 真让人怀念啊
A woman of modest taste, sorely missed.
或许我们该把那条 从Ramel那儿买的翡翠项链
Perhaps we should return the emerald necklace
退给他吧
we bought from Ramel.
嗯 它没啥用
Well, it was excessive,
如果钱能让你赶紧从竞技赌场抽身的话 我会…
and if the coin will help speed you from the pits I'd be…
两条都留着吧
Keep them both.
我不会让我太太 把珠宝退回去的
I will not have my wife return jewelry.
我要去洗个澡 我身上有死人的味道
I should wash, I smell of death.
不 你身上那是男人味
No, you smell like a man.
你还活着
You live.
我告诉过你 他不会死的
I told you he would.
Kerza怎样了？
What of Kerza?
输了
Fallen,
再也起不来了
never to rise whole.
这里是角斗士睡觉的地方
This is where gladiators sleep.
不是给狗睡的
Not dogs.
你说话注意点
Hold your tongue.
就算他现在没死
He stays,
早晚也要跟着Kerza下地狱
he wakes beside Kerza in the afterlife.
斯巴达克斯…
Spartacus…
别理那些混蛋
Pay no mind to those inbred fucks.
他们说得没错
They speak the truth.
我不再是角斗士了
I am no longer a gladiator.
你还是个男子汉
You are still a man.
是吗？
Am I?
值得人尊敬的男子汉
One deserving respect.
我觉得竞技赌场那种地方
Though I'll grant the pits could force
神仙也招架不住
Jupiter himself to doubt his cock.
关于竞技赌场 你知道些什么？
What do you know of the pits?
太多了
Too much.
我曾经在那里赌过
I wagered coin there at a time.
你在场围观？
You were of the crowd?
为鲜血嗥叫？
Howling for blood?
那种自豪感难以表达
Pride does not follow the statement.
这些斗士 斯巴达克斯 他们…
These fights, Spartacus, they're…
他们和竞技场上的人不同
they're different from the arena.
我亲眼见过 他们灵魂扭曲
I've seen them twist the mind,
从人变成野兽…
turning men into beasts…
变得是非不分
Their senses flown.
好好睡吧
Sleep, then.
做个美梦
And dream of better days.
你是想让我继续这么晒着 还是赶紧出个价？
Would you have me bake in the sun or offer a price?
14迪纳币
Fourteen denarii.
才14？
Fourteen?
几天前我买的时候 足足花了两倍这么多
That's half of what I paid not days ago.
二手货自然要跌价
Used gems fail to command full value.
哦
Oh.
哦 或许你在做珠宝生意吧
Oh, in the business of jewelry, perhaps.
真漂亮
A beautiful piece.
我想买下来
Allow me to buy from you.
原价哦
At full price.
你要送给哪个喜欢它的女人吗 Solonius？
You have a woman in mind who might favor it, Solonius?
没错
Indeed.
她近在眼前
She stands before me.
美人
A vision.
收着吧
Take it,
收着你的翡翠
and keep your emeralds.
光想象它们挂在你身上的样子 就让我心潮澎湃
The thought of them against your skin warms mine.
或许你是被晒晕了
Perhaps you mistake the heat of the sun.
成交了 Ramel
I'll have your offer, Ramel.
够拽
Pride.
我就喜欢你这拽样
Always part of your considerable attraction.
我丈夫也喜欢我这拽样
A trait which yet endears me to my husband.
他这些天过得怎样？
How is he fairing these days?
亲爱的Ovidius曾告诉过我
Beloved Ovidius mentioned something
他派人去竞技赌场打拳的事
about fighting his men in the pits.
哦 只是权宜之计
Oh, it's a temporary measure.
哦 当然
Oh, to be sure.
我希望 钱都流进他的荷包里
I pray fortune swiftly returns to his favored.
那样我们就能在竞技场再决胜负了
We may battle once again in arena.
为荣耀而战
With honor.
14迪纳币
Fourteen denarii.
不得好死的奸商
May the gods shrivel your cock.
弄清楚你对手的缺点
Study the flaws of your opponent.
以意志为剑
Strike with your mind as well as your sword.
在竞技场上鲁莽行事的话…
Fail to use your wits in the arena…
那就跟着斯巴达克斯
and risk tumbling after Spartacus
去竞技赌场吧
into the pits.
他一点也不可笑
The man is no base humor to be laughed at.
他是个警钟
He is a tale of caution.
吃饭的时候
Ponder on that
都好好想想吧
while you fill your bellies.
开饭！
Eat!
一点稀粥 一点水
A little porridge, and some water.
只够嘬一小口 但 你晓得的 正值旱季…
It's just a sip, but, you know, the drought…
Pietros啊！
Pietros!
离他远点！
Get away from him!
谢谢你
Thank you.
你那小子喜欢色雷斯人 对吧？
Your boy fancies the Thracian, does he?
他应付我还来不及呢
My cock keeps him well filled.
迦太基野兽！
The beast of Carthage!
我对你这绰号的由来 好奇万分
I always wondered how you acquired the name.
有话 就直说
If you have words of purpose, speak them.
我只是好奇而已 Crixus
I was merely curious, Crixus.
我帮你弄来的礼物
The gift I procured for you,
它还让人满意吗？
did it satisfy its intent?
礼物？
Gift?
一串猫眼石项链 用最好的…
An opal necklace, of the finest…
你太多嘴了！
Your tongue rattles too freely in your mouth!
管牢你那张嘴 否则哪天得跟你腿一样废掉
Secure it, or it will join that useless leg of yours.
抱歉
Apologies.
我是出于好意才问的
The question was born of good will,
你要相信我啊
I assure you.
让你的好意滚蛋去吧
Well you can stick your good will in your ass.
那家伙说的啥项链？
What necklace does the shit speak of?
没什么 别理他
It's nothing, best forgotten.
你疯了
You mad fuck.
那东西是要给 Lucretia那个小女奴的 对吧？
A trinket for Lucretia's pet, wasn't it?
别担心
Rest your mind.
我对Naevia没兴趣
I am of no interest to Naevia.
如果你还在乎自己这条命的话
Nor her to you, if you value your cock
就别打她的主意
attached to your balls.
Barca啊！
Barca!
照看好斯巴达克斯
See to Spartacus.
我要他在日落前 准备妥当
I want him ready to fight before the sun falls.
遵命 主人！
Yes, Dominus!
起来 畜生
Rise, dog.
让你赶死去呢
More death awaits.
靠！
Fuck!
他玩儿完了
He's finished.
就这么送那畜生去投胎！
That's how you send a dog to the afterlife!
斯巴达克斯 获胜！
Spartacus, victor!
斯巴达克斯的胜率猛涨啊
The odds soar in Spartacus' favor.
他们相信他战无不胜
They believe he's unbeatable.
怕死的人 一个也活不了
A dead man whose soul refuses to leave its body.
斯巴达克斯不怕死
Spartacus has no soul.
他是为了别人而活
It resides in the heart of another.
准备一下 下次跟Mytilus对打
Prepare yourself, you fight Mytilus next.
Crixus 主人传召你
Crixus, you are summoned.
谢谢
Thank you.
等等
Wait.
主人没耐心等
Domina will grow impatient.
你知道她是个急性子
You know the urgency of her desires.
她没传召你
She did not summon you.
那我来这儿干嘛？
Then why am I here?
那项链
The necklace,
你买给我的？
you purchased it for me?
我说过了
As I've said.
那为什么会在主人脖子上？
Then why does it grace the neck of Domina?
女人心 海底针！
The mind of a woman!
是你自己不要的 却跑来质问我
You deflect a gesture only to question where it lands.
你说过「我不能接受这个」
Your words were "I cannot accept this."
是啊 我说过
Yes, my words.
在人发现前 毁了它
Cut off before completion.
已经来不及了
Well then complete.
这东西我没法留下
That it is impossible for me to keep it,
无关欲望
regardless of desire.
我所有的东西
There is nothing in my possession
都是主人赏赐的
that was not given to me by Domina.
你不会笨到连这都忽略了吧？
Are you so thick that this fact was ignored?
你觉得她不会注意吗？
Did you think she would not notice?
我误会你把它还给我的意思了
I misunderstood your meaning in returning it.
你当然误会了！
Of course you misunderstood!
竞技场之外 你什么都不懂！
You have no mind outside the arena!
你只关注你的剑和盾牌
You think only with your sword and your shield,
你这个笨蛋 傻瓜…
you stupid, lumbering…
你真傻
You are a fool.
警卫！
Guard!
只有一个可活！
Only one survives!
杂种
Mongrel.
斯巴达克斯！
Spartacus!
获胜！
Victor!
还要多久？
How much longer?
在我们获得自由前 还要流多少血？
How much blood until we're free?
就快了
Soon.
我向你保证
I promise you.
只有想着抱着你…
Just the thought of holding you…
感觉你在我怀里…
Feeling you against me…
只有这样 我才觉得自己还活着
It's the only thing that keeps my heart beating.
你看上去萎靡不振
You look like shit.
我还扛得住
I've endured worse.
谁能扛得住
What man could,
你还把自己当这世上的人看吗？
and still count himself of this world?
这个世界 满是痛苦
This world. All it holds is suffering.
总有一天会结束的
It will end one day.
我们会再聚首的
And we will be reunited.
作为角斗士吗？
As gladiators?
这主意倒不错
A welcomed thought.
这是支持我活着的唯一信念
One that keeps me from the grasp of the afterlife.
你看上去可不太妙
Your condition speaks to its encroachment.
这是曼德拉草根
Mandrake root,
从Ashur那儿弄到的
acquired from Ashur.
嚼着可以止痛
Chewed to numb the pain.
拿着吧
Take it.
我不能
I can't.
我需要保持意识清醒 来救你
I need what remains of my senses to save you.
救我干啥？
Save me from what?
斯巴达克斯？
Spartacus?
谢谢你的好意
Your offer is well received.
我心领了
Even in the turning away of it.
斯巴达克斯赚回来这么多
Spartacus handsomely returns.
这些钱够还债了吗？
Will the sum balance our debts?
尽管挣了这么多…
The scales are well nudged…
但是还债？
But balanced?
还不够
No.
把其它债都还了
Pay out the most egregious.
但先别还Ovidius的
But leave Ovidius with empty fucking hands.
Ovidius么？
Ovidius?
行政官的兄弟？
The magistrate's cousin?
挺晚了 你该去睡了
You should be in bed, the hour is late.
我们还欠了他的债
And our debts follow.
如果欠着Ovidius的债…
If money is owed to Ovidius…
那到期就该还清
Then it will be paid, in due course.
那个人侮辱了我 我可不会以德报怨
The man offered me insult and I won't reward it with it swift coin.
没搞错吧？
Is that wise?
如果他向行政官诉苦 我担心…
If he complains to the magistrate, I worry…
我是一家之主 这些事留给我烦就好！
I am the paterfamilias, the worry is mine alone!
你每天早上醒过来都这样？
Is that how you woke this morning?
一个人？
Alone?
我没在你旁边吗？
Was I not by your side?
Lucretia啊…
Lucretia…
这些钱 你是怎么弄来的？
How did you come to possess those coins?
Lucretia啊！
Lucretia!
Lucretia啊…
Lucretia…
从Ramel那儿弄来的 如果你非要知道的话
From Ramel, if you must know,
我去退了那条翡翠项链
in exchange for the emerald necklace.
我明令告诉过你 别做这种事！
I commanded you to do no such thing!
明令？
Commanded?
你把我错当成奴隶了吧
You mistake me for a slave.
你知道我不是这意思
You know my intentions better.
Lucretia 那些翡翠…
Lucretia, the emeralds…
你戴着很漂亮的
They looked lovely on you.
去把它们弄回来吧 破费点小钱而已…
To see them returned, a casualty of ill finances…
错在我
The fault was mine,
天天想着买东西
in pressing the purchase in the first place.
你的烦恼 就是我的烦恼 Quintus
Your worries are my worries, Quintus.
你从来都不是一个人
You are never alone.
你真贴心
A notion to warm the heart.
翡翠项链
The emerald necklace,
退了多少钱？
what did it bring?
14迪纳币
Fourteen denarii.
才14？
Fourteen?
前几天买的时候 可花了两倍钱那么多啊！
Days past it commanded twice that!
女人一碰生意 就是这么个结果！
Women and business, and these are the results!
Solonius路过的时候
An offer for the full price was made by Solonius,
本想原价买去
who happened by.
我难道应该卖给他吗？
Better business had I accepted?
你应该再多要一点的
You struck the wiser bargain.
Solonius知道你参与竞技赌场的事
Solonius knows of your activities in the pits.
现在全城的人都知道了
The whole city does by now.
让他们去说
Let their tongues wag.
赢的钱可以把训练场的债还清
The winnings will return this ludus to solvency.
然后 我们就可以堵上Solonius和他那些人的嘴了
Then we'll have at Solonius and all his shit eaters.
那个色雷斯人能坚持多久？
How long can the Thracian last?
照那样下去 只有几天而已吧
A handful of nights, if that.
就算是具行尸走肉 早晚也得玩完
Even the walking dead eventually return to the grave.
把他送回竞技赌场去！
Send him back to the pits!
他不是角斗士！
He's not a fucking gladiator!
斯巴达克斯！
Spartacus!
拿着它 斯巴达克斯
Here take it, Spartacus.
你干得不错 斯巴达克斯
You have fought well, Spartacus.
神明会奖赏你的
The gods reward you.
承诺兑现了
The promise is kept.
Sura啊…
Sura…
我会永远和你在一起…
I will always be with you…
哪怕是死
Even in death.
暴雨要来了
The rains are coming.
救救我
Save me.
在它们冲走一切迹象之前
Before they wash everything away.
Sura啊…
Sura…
不…
No…
不！
No!
他现在没多少斗志了 对吧？
Not so much fight in him now, is there?
他在为竞技赌场蓄势待发
He saves his fury for the pits.
在那地方 你早晚要死
A place you wouldn't last a fucking breath.
斯巴达克斯
Spartacus.
你干得很好
You've fought well.
神明终将赐福于你
The gods may yet reward you.
神明
The gods.
他们昨晚显灵了
They came to me last night.
就在我的梦中
In a dream.
神明向你释意何事？
What did they show you?
真相
The truth.
你用我的命赚钱一事 今晚到头了
Your profit from my blood ends tonight.
你若拒绝出战 我将停止
Refuse to fight, and I will cease my attempts
搜寻你妻子
to find your wife.
我必须救她
I have to save her.
在暴雨来临前
Before the rains come.
少跟我说胡话 你这个疯子！
Give way to your meaning, you mad fuck!
我的赔率依旧居高不下？
The odds remain high in my favor?
没错
Still.
那就将赌注全部押到我身上
Then bet everything you have against me.
你会死在竞技赌场吗？
You would die in the pits?
你会愿意让我时来运转？
Willingly, to see my fortune rise?
嗯 只要你愿意继续从叙利亚人那里
Yes, if you will hold to wrest my wife
寻找我妻子 哪怕消息少得可怜
from the Syrian with a piece of it.
一旦你死了
What's to keep me to this bargain
我干嘛还要继续这么做？
once your blood is spilled?
为了荣誉
Honor.
还有 若是你违背了承诺
And the promise of vengeance from the afterlife
我做鬼也不放过你
if you betray it.
成交
The deal is struck.
带着你的诚意出战
Make it appear a sincere fight.
帮他准备妥当
Finish preparing him.
看哪…
Behold…
斯巴达克斯！
Spartacus!
还有Ixion！
Behold, Ixion!
赌注已下？
The wager is placed?
已分散下到各个赌盘
The sum has been spread among
以防引起怀疑
the brokers to ease suspicion.
神明将会
What weapons
赐予他们何种武器？
shall the gods bless them with?
或是天谴他们
Or curse them
空手作战？
with empty hands?
命运掌握在你们自己手里！
Choose your fate!
Ixion选择战斧！
Ixion draws bipennis!
斯巴达克斯选择弯剑！
Spartacus draws sica!
规则只有一条！
We have but a single rule!
只能有一个活下来！
Only one survives!
相互厮打
Mongrel on mongrel,
直到死神降临！
till Charon arrives!
早着呢 早着呢…
Not yet, not yet…
不！
No!
明明有侍卫 却还让我站在这儿流血！
My protector, and here I stand bloodied!
我没发觉还有旁人
I did not see there was another.
你必须确保我万无一失！
You must see all when my life is in the balance!
两只眼睛给我瞪大点
Ring your crown with eyes, or have the two you possess
否则我替你全挖出来！
ripped from your fucking skull!
他们皮肤上有烙印 主人
Their flesh carries a brand, Dominus.
代表什么含义？
Of what origin?
不清楚
Unfamiliar,
但可以确定是奴隶的烙印
but certainly the mark of a slave.
奴隶？
Slaves?
他们派
They send
他妈的普通奴隶
common fucking slaves
来杀Batiatus！
to kill Batiatus!
他妈的普通奴隶？
Common fucking slaves?
靠！
Fuck!
我靠！
找到他们的主人
Discover their master.
我要问清楚这件事
I wish to have words with him.
朱诺的唇
Juno's lips,
朱诺的心
Juno's heart,
朱诺的腹
Juno's belly.
我知道时间了
The kalends are upon us.
每个月的第一天
The first day of the new month.
敬上祭品
Prepare a sacrifice.
或许神明会赐予我们一个孩子
Perhaps the gods will finally grace us
作为回报…
with a child in return…
Quintus啊！
Quintus!
呃 没什么 一个小麻烦
Aye, it's nothing, a minor annoyance.
小麻烦？
Minor?
为什么提到孩子
Why do you speak of children,
还差点让我成了寡妇？
yet press to make me a widow?
想要我死
It will take more than a scratch
这点小伤算什么
to wrest me from your side.
别说了 快坐下
Barely more, sit.
告诉我 谁那么该死
And tell me who must die in response.
杀手已经开赴赌场
The agents have already been dispatched to the underworld.
还不知道谁是幕后主使
The hand behind them yet to be revealed.
我警告过你 竞技赌场很危险
I warned you of the dangers of the pits.
我以为今晚之后
I had thought to erase all our debts
我们能还清所有债务
through them after tonight.
斯巴达克斯打算全力一搏
Spartacus offered terms to see it so.
搏什么？
What terms?
他连命都押上了
His willing death to wager upon.
只为找到他的妻子
Locating his wife the crux of the bargain.
那个色雷斯人死了？
The Thracian is dead?
没有 他还活着
No, he yet lives.
但赌注没了
And the wager is lost.
多少？
How much?
很大一笔
A substantial sum.
我们没拿到！
We don't have it!
那个色雷斯人…
That Thracian…
他带给我们家族的 尽是耻辱！
He brings nothing but shame on our house!
若不是他
Were it not for him,
你早就成寡妇了
you would be a widow.
他今天在竞技赌场救了我的命
He saved my life in the pits this night.
若不是因为他 你永远不会去那种地方
A place you would never have been if it weren't for him.
他被诅咒了 他受到天谴
He is cursed, he is cursed by the gods.
我盼着他死呢 他早就该死了
I would see his life ended, as it should have been
他迈入竞技场时 就注定受死
when he stepped into the arena, doomed for execution.
只要这个色雷斯人多活一天
Every day that the Thracian yet lives,
我怕噩运就会降临到咱们头上
I fear that his curse becomes our own.
斯巴达克斯
Spartacus.
主人传唤你
Batiatus summons you.
我妻子认为你受到天谴了
My wife thinks you are cursed by the gods.
我觉得也像
I'm inclined to agree.
我没意见
You'll find no argument.
理智的做法是 在你影响到我之前
The rational course would be to end your miserable life
结束你悲惨的生活
before it further infects mine.
你已给过承诺
A promise was made,
你会去找Sura
you would find Sura.
前提是如果你死在竞技赌场
If you died in the pits.
可你还在这儿站着呢 活生生的
Yet here you stand, alive.
你也一样
As do you.
诺言仍然有效
Promise is kept.
我会继续搜寻她
I will continue the search for her.
你救了我的命
You saved my life.
欠债还钱 天经地义
Gods or not, a debt demands repayment.
他一旦康复 就让他重归角斗士队伍吧
He's to rejoin the gladiators as soon as he is able.